Register to the Lev Nikolaevich Litoshenko papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Lev Nikolaevich Litoshenko papers
1925-1927
27002
Litoshenko, Lev Nikolaevich, 1886-.
6 manuscript boxes, 1 envelope (2.5 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives. Stanford, California 94305-6010
Writings and photographs, relating to agriculture in the Soviet Union and industry in the United States. Includes drafts and final typescript of "Agrarian Policy in Soviet Russia before the Adoption of the Five Year Plan" (co-authored with Lincoln Hutchinson), and typescript of "Metody finansirovaniia amerikanskoi promyshlennosti." Writings sponsored by the Committee on Russian Research, Hoover War Library.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1927.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the library catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical/Historical Note
Russian economist.
Scope and Content of Collection
Writings and photographs, relating to agriculture in the Soviet Union and industry in the United States. Includes drafts and final typescript of "Agrarian Policy in Soviet Russia before the Adoption of the Five Year Plan" (co-authored with Lincoln Hutchinson), and typescript of "Metody finansirovaniia amerikanskoi promyshlennosti." Writings sponsored by the Committee on Russian Research, Hoover War Library.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Agriculture--Soviet Union.; Soviet Union--Economic policy--1917-1928.; United States--Industries.; Economists.; Hutchinson, Lincoln.; Hoover Institution on War, Revolution and Peace.
Container List
- "Agrarian Policy in Soviet Russia," 593 pages (in duplicate), 1927 (Box 1)
  - Introduction and table of contents (Box 2)
  - "The Land Question Before the Revolution" (Box 2)
  - "The Land Crisis and Its Causes" (Box 2)
  - "Improvement in Agricultural Conditions in the Early Years of the 20th Century" (Box 2)
  - "The Influence of the World War" (Box 2)
  - "Three Years of Socialistic Experiment" (Box 2)
  - "The Russian Revolution and Agriculture" (Box 2)
  - "The Conflict of Parties After the First Revolution" (Box 2)
  - "The Bolsheviks as Friends of the Peasantry" (Box 2)
  - "The Real Attitude of the Peasantry" (Box 2)
  - "Class Conflict as a Method of Polititcal Strategy" (Box 2)
  - "Backing the 'Average Peasant': Cultural Propaganda" (Box 2)
  - "Ruin of Agriculture" (Box 2)
  - "The Causes of the Ruin of Agriculture" (Box 2)
  - "Degeneration of Peasant Farming" (Box 2)
  - "The New Economic Policy" (Box 2)
    - General (Box 2)
  - "The Food Policy" (Box 2)
  - "The Food Taxes of 1921" (Box 2)
  - "Similarities and Differences Between the Food Levy and the Food Tax" (Box 2)
  - "Separation of Food Supply Policy from Tax Policy" (Box 2)
  - "The Agricultural Tax" (Box 2)
  - "The Isolated Character of Peasant Taxation" (Box 2)
  - "The Fundamental Purposes of the Agricultural Taxation" (Box 2)
  - "The Fiscal Interests" (Box 2)
  - "The Social-Political Aims" (Box 2)
  - "The Interests of Agricultural Production" (Box 2)
  - "The Mechanism of Taxation" (Box 2)
  - "Price Policy and the Purchasing System" (Box 2)
  - "The Significance of the Agricultural Market" (Box 2)
  - "Land Legislation" (Box 2)
  - "Land Settlement" (Box 2)
  - "Direct Assistance to Peasant Farms" (Box 2)
    - "Material Assistance to the Peasant Farms" (Box 2)
    - "Precautions Against Natural Calamites" (Box 2)
    - "Advisory and Experimental Work" (Box 2)
    - "The Importance of Agricultural Assistance to the Peasantry" (Box 2)
  - "Agricultural Cooperation" (Box 2)
    - "The Theory of Agrarian Cooperation" (Box 2)
    - "General Results of Agricultural Cooperation" (Box 2)
    - "Collective Organizations" (Box 2)
    - "Basic Functions of Agricultural Cooperation" (Box 2)
    - "The Commercial Activity of Agricultural Cooperation" (Box 2)
    - "Credit Functions of Agricultural Cooperation" (Box 2)
    - "The Social Composition of Agricultural Cooperatives" (Box 2)
    - "General Conclusion as to Agricultural Cooperation" (Box 3)
  - "Some Results of the New Economic Policy" (Box 3)
    - "Production" (Box 3)
    - "Distribution of Rurual Incomes" (Box 3)
    - "Conclusion" (Box 3)
  - "Dilemma: The Inevitable Antithesis Between Land Food Policy" (Box 3)
  - "Evolutionary Communism" (Box 3)
  - "Fate of the Socialist Forms of Agriculture" (Box 3)
  - Graphs, tables, etc. (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous drafts, notes, etc. (Box 3)
  - Notes to the Introduction (Box 3)
  - Notes to Part I (Box 3)
  - Notes to Part II (Box 4)
  - Notes to Part III (Box 4)
  - "Russian Agriculture and the Famine of 1921" (Box 4)
- "Agrarian Policy in Soviet Russia" (in Russian) (Box 4)
  - "Introduction" (Box 4)
  - "New Economic Policy" (Box 4)
  - "Socialist Economy in 1918-1920" (Box 4)
  - "The Change to the New Policy" (Box 4)
  - "The Retreat" (Box 4)
  - "The Structure of Soviet Economy" (Box 4)
  - "Outward Peculiarites of the Soviet Economic System" (Box 4)
  - "Evolutionary Communism" (Box 4)
  - "Separation of Food Supply From Tax Policy" (Box 4)
  - "The Isolated Character of Peasant Taxation" (Box 4)
  - "The Fiscal Interests" (Box 4)
  - "The Social-Political Aims" (Box 4)
  - "The Burden of Taxation" (Box 4)
  - "The Price Policy" (Box 4)
  - "Land Legislation" (Box 4)
  - "The Land Code of 1922" (Box 4)
  - "Rights and Duties of Land Holder" (Box 4)
  - "The Present Land Code Compared with its Predecessors" (Box 4)
  - "Land Settlement" (Box 4)
  - "Land Improvements" (Box 4)
  - "Conclusion" (Box 4)
  - "Direct Assistance to Peasant Farms" (Box 4)
  - "Material Assistance to the Present Farms" (Box 4)
  - "Precautions Against Natural Calamities" (Box 4)
  - "Advisory and Experimental Work" (Box 4)
  - "The Importance of Agricultural Assistance to the Peasantry" (Box 4)
  - "Agricultural Cooperation" (Box 5)
  - "The Theory of Agrarian Cooperation" (Box 5)
  - "General Results of Agricultural Cooperation" (Box 5)
  - "Collective Organizations" (Box 5)
  - "Basic Functions of Agricultural Cooperation" (Box 5)
  - "The Commercial Activity of Agricultural Cooperation of Agricultural Cooperation" (Box 5)
  - "Credit Functions of Agricultural Cooperatives" (Box 5)
  - "The Social Composition of Agricultural Cooperatives" (Box 5)
  - "General Conclusion As to Agricultural Cooperation" (Box 5)
  - "Some Results of the New Economic Policy" (Box 5)
    - "Production" (Box 5)
    - "Distribution of Rural Incomes" (Box 5)
    - "Conclusions" (Box 5)
  - "Land Settlement Policy" (Box 5)
  - "Agriculture in Soviet Economy" (Box 5)
  - "The New Economic Policy" (Box 5)
    - "General" (Box 5)
    - "The Food Policy" (Box 5)
    - "The Food Taxes of 1921" (Box 5)
    - "Similarities and Differences Between the Food Levy and the Food Tax" (Box 5)
    - "Separation of Food Supply Policy From Tax Policy" (Box 5)
    - "The Agricultural Tax" (Box 5)
    - "The Isolated Character of Peasant Taxation" (Box 5)
    - "The Fundamental Purposes of Agricultural Taxation" (Box 5)
    - "Fiscal Interests" (Box 5)
    - "The Social-Political Aims" (Box 5)
    - "The Interests of Agricultural Production" (Box 5)
    - "The Mechanism of Taxation' (Box 5)
    - "The Burden of Taxation" (Box 5)
    - "Some Conclusions" (Box 5)
  - "Land Legislation" (Box 5)
    - "General" (Box 5)
    - "The Land code of 1922" (Box 5)
    - "The Idea of Land Nationalization" (Box 5)
    - "Who is Entitled to the Use of Land" (Box 5)
    - "Method of Land Distribution" (Box 5)
    - "Rights and Duties of Land Holders" (Box 5)
    - "Agencies Carrying Out the Provision of the Land Law" (Box 5)
    - "The Present Land Code Compared with its Predecessors" (Box 5)
    - "Economic Results of the Soviet Land Law" (Box 5)
  - "Land Settlement" (Box 5)
    - "General" (Box 5)
    - "Land Settlement" (Box 5)
    - "Migration" (Box 5)
    - "Land Improvements" (Box 5)
    - "Conclusion" (Box 5)
  - "Some Results of the New Economic Policy" (Box 5)
    - "General" (Box 5)
    - "Production" (Box 5)
    - "Distribution of Rural Incomes" (Box 5)
    - "Conclusion" (Box 5)
  - "Price Policy and the Purchasing System" (Box 5)
    - "The Significance of the Agricultural System" (Box 5)
    - "Methods of Regulation" (Box 5)
    - "The Price Policy" (Box 5)
    - "Prices and Agricultural Production" (Box 5)
  - Books used by L.N. Litoshenko, a list (in Russian) (Box 5)
- Increment, August 1981 (Box 6)
  - "Agrarian Policy in Soviet Russia," Incomplete drafts, n.d. (Box 6)
- Increment, May 1992 (Box 6)
  - "Metody Finansirovaniia Amerikanskoi Promyshlennosti,", n.d. (Box 6)